Patrick Blesi

920 N Hermitage Avenue Unit 2, Chicago, IL 60622 | 952.649.7542 | patrick@ble.si | patrick.ble.si

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY:

Focused and dedicated individual with 5+ years industry experience as a software engineer, technical lead, and manager, leading teams to deliver products through the full software development life cycle and a proven track record of delivering results.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE:

Tech Lead, Manager (Platform Group) - Braintree (PayPal), Chicago, IL

October 2016 - Present

- Managed 2 teams of 4 engineers to improve deployment and development processes and scale our data layer
- Improved deployment process of main payment processing application by parallelizing deployment of background systems,
 adding canary deployments, and enabling out-of-band database migrations
- Upgraded main payment processing application from Rails 4 to Rails 5

Tech Lead (Support Developers) - Braintree (PayPal), Chicago, IL

June 2015 – September 2016

- Lead team of 7 engineers, developing sample Braintree integrations in 6 different languages, improving server sdks, reducing support ticket, stack overflow, and github issue response times from weeks to hours
- Implemented threading model using channels to parallelize import process to eliminate race conditions and triple throughput for a single process

Senior Software Engineer (Pay with PayPal) - Braintree (PayPal), Chicago, IL

June 2014 – June 2015

- Developed main integration to PayPal rest API through Braintree
- Lead development of PayPal browser-switch feature to allow mobile users to store credentials for fast, easy checkout

Software Engineer - Wowzers Llc, Chicago, IL

September 2013 – June 2014

- Developed Ruby on Rails full stack implementation of student grade reporting feature
- Created naïve Bayes classifier classifying user feedback into one of four categories, achieving 87% accuracy.
- Developed Ruby on Rails sales dashboard utilizing Hub Spot and Salesforce APIs to aggregate data.

Software Engineer - Higi Llc, Chicago, IL

August 2012 - September 2013

- Developed customer-facing analytics platform integrating JSON database, MSFT SQL Server, and Tableau Server to synthesize web, mobile, and kiosk data for 500,000+ users, 6,000,000+ records.
- Developed redundant, fault-tolerant, high availability Twitter monitoring daemon to process user submitted photos via Twitter, Instagram, Twitpic, and yfrog clients.
- Developed C# Facebook and Twitter API clients for querying user info, posting messages, creating app invites, and monitoring twitter streams.

Mathematics Teacher - Teach For America, Chicago, IL

June 2011 – August 2012

- Prestigiously selected as one of 5,300 candidates out of 45,000 applicants (12% acceptance rate) to teach Algebra, Geometry, and Algebra II in an urban school district.
- Facilitated student learning which led students to achieve over 2 years of growth in mathematical reasoning ability.

All-Team Lead, Software Team Lead - IEEE Robotics Team, UW-Madison

August 2010 – June 2011

- Leader of administrative and software development for 35 member organization.
- Directly managed design and development of robotic control networking software framework (JAUS) in Java via UDP.

Research Assistant – Biostatistics Department, UW-Madison

May 2010 – January 2011

- Selected to head research project developing machine learning algorithms in MATLAB detecting statistically significant connections of brain regions in MRI data in order to classify brain pathologies
- Implemented independent component analysis, L1-regularized least squares regression, L1-regularized logistic regression machine learning algorithms on autoregressive models

TECHNICAL SKILLS (IN ORDER OF FAMILIARITY):

Programming Languages: Ruby, SQL, Java, C#, JavaScript, Bash, Haskell

Technologies: Ruby On Rails, Postgres, Rspec, Puppet, Capistrano, Bootstrap, Redis

Operating Systems: 14+ years working with Unix-based operating systems.

Development Tools: vim, git, tmux, emacs, PostgreSQL, Eclipse, Visual Studio

EDUCATION: University of Wisconsin-Madison

May 2011

Bachelor of Science: Math & Computer Science

Honors: Dean's List Fall 2009, Fall 2007

RELEVANT COURSEWORK:

Math: Calculus Series, Linear Algebra, Differential Equations, Geometry, Combinatorics, Number Theory, Analysis, Abstract Algebra

Computer Science: Data Structures, Algorithms, Operating Systems, XV6 Kernel Development, Networking, Databases, Compilers, HCI, Artificial Intelligence, Computer Graphics, Linear Programming